joker.com 2019-09-26

# Imprint - Joker.com

**CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH d/b/a Joker.com**  
Hansaallee 191-193  
DE-40549 Duesseldorf  
Germany  
Fax: +49 211 86767 6449  
GF (CEO): Renate Altmann-Spangenberg   
Contact: [info[AT]joker[DOT]com](https://joker.com/goto/support)

Registered at Handelsregister Duesseldorf: HRB34900  
UST-IdNr.: DE121641016

#### Legal Notice

**Liability disclaimer**

As a service provider, according to § 7 Abs.1 TMG, we are responsible for our own content on these pages according to the general laws. However, as a service provider, according to §§ 8 to 10 TMG we are not obligated to supervise transmitted or stored third-party information or to investigate circumstances which indicate an illegal activity.   
Obligations to remove or block the use of information according to general laws remain unaffected. Liability in this regard, however, is only possible from the time of knowledge of a concrete infringement. We will immediately remove such content if we become aware of any such legal violations. 

**Links to external websites**

Our offer contains links to external websites of third parties on whose content we have no influence on. Therefore, we are not liable for this foreign content. The respective provider or owner of these foreign pages is always responsible for the content of these linked pages. The linked pages were checked for possible legal violations at the time of linking. Illegal content was not recognizable at the time of linking.   
A permanent control of the content of the linked pages is not reasonable without concrete indications of an infringement. If we become aware of any legal infringements, we will immediately remove such links. 

**Copyright**

The content and works created by the site operators on these pages are subject to German copyright law. Copying, processing, distribution and any kind of usage outside the limits of copyright laws require the written consent of the respective author or creator. Downloads and copies of this site are only permitted for private, non-commercial use.   
Insofar as the contents on this site were not created by the operator, the copyrights of third parties are respected. In particular contents of third parties are marked as such. If you are nevertheless aware of a copyright infringement, we ask for a corresponding note. If we become aware of legal violations, we will immediately remove such content. 

**PGP/GPG public key:**

                        -----BEGIN PGP PUBLIC KEY BLOCK-----
                        Version: GnuPG v1.0.7 (GNU/Linux)
    
                        mIsEPOorJQEEAJauWOOvusxn9GFEPjZnQ3x/48OfaPwSN4cIF5ezpUT6FycZQa+q
                        eUnNlS+bj80ULXnyyigmkUGwEtW/Qoyd55RM983pr4KtuHSMSU9gCN1syuHlDOAm
                        71u6irfv5RaHbJXauMCAgUKn+dBNZVZyUTm9aW2pudcwY45apF2tieTZAAYptClq
                        b2tlci5jb20gc2lnbmVyIHNlcnZpY2UgPGluZm9Aam9rZXIuY29tPoiyBBMBAgAc
                        BQI8/NifAhsDBAsHAwIDFQIDAxYCAQIeAQIXgAAKCRAm3eE0EUTiIx9RA/9HGDrD
                        cVM6PjZHr5jpT4svpv7xrjVRn2OIR+s80RuBAnLyAWOflqJ9342SYD8C7BMAqYm4
                        wXvC3/yvbQEAqsmJ5Bbq2NV+KDepahTtL8SUQ6TkOSUd9NDOvLoQWVI6o1Dz/3MG
                        HLJfNtx6067Sq8pP8PuYyscPyZ7/uiUilyOrqg==
                        =O/7Q
                        -----END PGP PUBLIC KEY BLOCK-----

_Version 25.5.2018_

Joker.com attaches particular importance to data protection.  
A use of the internet pages of Joker.com is basically possible without any indication of personal data. However, if a data subject wishes to make use of special services of our company via our website, the processing of personal data may become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no legal basis for such processing, we generally obtain the consent of the data subject.

The processing of personal data, such as the name, address, e-mail address or telephone number of a data subject, is always carried out in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and in accordance with the country- specific data protection regulations applicable to Joker.com. By means of this privacy policy declaration, our company would like to inform the public about the type, scope and purpose of the personal data collected, used and processed by us. Furthermore, data subjects will be informed of their rights by means of this data protection declaration.

**Name and address of the responsible data controller**

The person responsible within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation, other data protection laws in force in the Member States of the European Union and other provisions of a data protection nature is:

                        CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH
                        Hansaallee 191-193
                        40549 Düsseldorf
                        Deutschland
                        Tel.: +49 (211) 86767-0
                        info[@]joker[.]com

The data protection officer of the controller can be contacted directly at the above address and additionally via:

datenschutz[@]joker.com

Especially for domain registrations data processing may happen, which CSL GmbH cannot control itself. Other data controllers are involved here, depending on the domain type the operating registry, or in the case of generic top-level domains the organization ICANN as joint data controller of the registry and the registrar.

**What is ‘personal Data‘?**

Personal data are all information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter "data subject"). Identifiable is a natural person who can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by assignment to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or one or more special characteristics that express the physical, physiological, genetic, psychological, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

**What personal information is processed at Joker.com?**

We process data that you voluntarily provide to us, data that we automatically collect when you visit websites, use our service interfaces ("API") and purchase our products. The personal data that we process as inventory data about our customers include:  

  * first name, last name
  * email address
  * phone number
  * fax number (if available))
  * postal address
  * name of your organisation (if available)
  * preferred language
  * IP address (in case of an order)
  * login name
  * products and services ordered
  * type of payment, and accordingly (withouit storage): 
    * Paypal account email
    * Credit card number, verification code
    * Bank account number

Additional personal data may also be requested if necessary for the requested service.

**Our processing of third party data**

If you transfer personal data of third parties within the scope of ordering a service, i.e. you use their personal data as contact or additional contact, you are obliged to inform the person concerned about the use, about this data protection regulations and to obtain the necessary consent for this use and to prove it upon request.

**What is personal data processed for?**

The information you provide when requesting a service (such as domain registration) or processing or updating support requests is necessary to establish a contractual relationship between you and us. This is necessary to provide the requested services and the related products.

Furthermore, this data is necessary for the proper management of your Joker.com customer account in order to enable us to prevent misuse, to provide you with the necessary information, e.g. regarding domain extensions, and to comply with applicable legal requirements.

The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 I b) of the GDPR.

It may be necessary, on the basis and in accordance with Article 6 I (f) of the GDPR, to transfer personal data to service providers who act as data controllers for you in the provision of the requested service, such as in particular registries and ICANN.   
The legitimate interests of data controllers include  

  * the establishment of a contractual relationship between you and CSL GmbH
  * the prevention of abuse or fraud
  * compliance with the regulations applicable to services such as domain registrations
  * ensuring data consistency and completeness
  * the guarantee of a continued service in the event of business failure of CSL GmbH

In certain cases, the transmission of personal data may be necessary in order to comply with applicable legal obligations pursuant to Art. 6 I c) GDPR. This is pointed out separately in applicable cases in the registration conditions of the respective domain types.

Your data collected within the scope of a domain registration can also be processed within the scope of a data escrow procedure to guarantee a continued service in the event of a business failure of CSL GmbH and transferred to third parties in order to protect the registration of your domain.

In certain cases in which we must protect the legitimate interests of third parties in accordance with Art. 6 I f) GDPR, personal data may be disclosed to these third parties, provided that these interests are not invalidated by your fundamental rights.

If we receive your explicit and informed consent, we may also pass on your personal data to external service providers. This concerns e.g. your explicit consent to make your domain registration data public, despite the offered possibilities to suppress such a publication.   
Such consent can be revoked at any time.

**Who does Joker.com share your personal information with?**

Joker.com or CSL GmbH will never sell your data to third parties. As far as legally provided and permitted, your data can be passed on to the following possible parties:  

  * third-party providers directly involved in the provision of your ordered service, such as the registry of the ordered top-level domain pursuant to Art. 49 1 b) GDPR; please note the registration conditions of the relevant registry. This may also include the transmission of personal data to parties outside the European Union, which is directly dependent on your selection of the desired top-level domain and cannot be influenced by us. In this case, however, you will be informed of this fact and may object to the registration. The respective data privacy policies can also be found at <https://joker.com/goto/tc>
  * third parties directly involved in payment transactions, such as PayPal, SIX Payment Services for credit card payments, and banks for account payments, with the relevant data privacy policies: 
    * Paypal: <https://joker.com/goto/dp_paypal>
    * Six: <https://joker.com/goto/dp_six>
  * within the framework of a data escrow procedure to authorised and certified service providers, currently this is: 
    * DENIC eG: <https://joker.com/goto/dp_rde>
  * law enforcement and other authorities or civil organizations with authorization under applicable laws and regulations
  * in individual cases, address verification service providers to ensure the data accuracy of domain registration data

**What rights do you have with regard to your data?**

You have the right to access and correct your data via your customer account with us.  
You have the right to request information about your stored data or to request a copy of your data.  
You have the right to request the correction of any incomplete or outdated data at any time.  
You have the right to object to the processing of certain data or certain processing activities.  
If the processing activity is based on your consent, this consent can be revoked by you at any time.  
You have the right to delete your personal data if the deletion is legally permissible, data processing is no longer necessary or there is no longer any legal basis for data processing.  
You have the right to information if we have received your data from third parties for processing.

To exercise your rights, you can [contact](https://joker.com/?mode=support&support_type=data_request) employees of CSL GmbH at any time. You also have the right to lodge complaints with a supervisory authority.

**Storage and retention of data**

The criterion for the duration of the storage of personal data is the respective legal retention period. After the expiry of this period, the corresponding data will be routinely deleted, provided that it is no longer necessary for the fulfilment or initiation of the contract. Only data that is actually required is stored.

Backup copies in our backup systems are automatically deleted with a time delay. Contract data will be deleted after the legal retention period has expired.

Log data that is generated when you visit our website or use our services is only collected if this is necessary for the provision of services and payment transactions.

This log data includes the IP address of the device with which you access the website or a service, the type of browser you use, the website you have previously visited, your system configuration and the date and time. The IP addresses are always stored anonymously. Log data will not be stored for longer than six months after the time required for invoicing and the provision of the service.

Access data to your customer account are always stored encrypted according to the state of the art, payment data for PayPal or credit card payments are only stored anonymously.

Automated decision making or the creation of user profiles does not take place.

**Cookies**

The Internet pages of CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH use cookies. Cookies are text files which are stored on your device via an Internet browser.

By using cookies, CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH can provide users of this website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without cookies.

When you visit our website, we may require your consent to store certain information on your devices in the form of a cookie in order to better provide you with our services.

If you deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our website may be fully usable.

**Privacy policy regarding the use of Matomo (formerly Piwik)**

CSL GmbH has integrated the Matomo component on this website. Matomo is an open source software tool for web analysis. Web analysis is the collection and evaluation of data on the behaviour of visitors to Internet sites. A web analysis is mainly used to optimize a website.

The software is operated on servers of CSL GmbH; the data protection-sensitive log files are stored exclusively on these servers. Matomo places a cookie on the device that you use to access our website. By setting the cookie, we are able to analyze the use of our website. As part of this technical procedure, we obtain knowledge of personal data, such as your IP address, which among other things serves us to trace the origin of visitors and clicks.  
The only personal data which is linked to the data collected by Matomo is the visitor’s IP address, which is anonymized additionally.  
This personal data is stored by us.  
We do not pass this personal data on to third parties.  
You can explicitly object to the collection by Matomo by using the option of "opt-out", which we offer on our website.

You are not being tracked since your browser is reporting that you do not want to. This is a setting of your browser so you won't be able to opt-in until you disable the 'Do Not Track' feature. 

Furthermore, our internet pages follow the "Do-not-Track"-policy, which most common browsers offer, and in case of activation by you, generally prevent data collection by Matomo.

**Data Privacy**

CSL GmbH as operator of this site takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your personal data confidentially and in accordance with the legal data protection regulations, the [ICANN Model Privacy Policy](https://joker.com/goto/icann_regpriv) and this data protection statement.   
At the order of the local authorities, we may provide information on this data in individual cases, as far as this is necessary for the purposes of law enforcement, security, the fulfillment of the statutory tasks of the constitutional protection authorities or the military shielding service or the enforcement of intellectual property rights.   
We would like to point out that data transmission on the Internet (for example, when communicating via e-mail) can present security vulnerabilities. An absolute protection of the data regarding access by third parties is not possible. 

**Scope of this declaration**

This data protection statement applies to the websites of CSL GmbH d/b/a joker.com, available at https://joker.com and https://rpanel.io. Based on the [ICANN Model Privacy Policy](https://joker.com/goto/icann_regpriv), for the purpose of registering domain names, updates of existing doman names or other services in the context of domain registrations, you are requested to transmit the following information: 

  * name of desired domain
  * name and address of the designated owner (registrant) of the domain
  * technical information regarding name service and about the computer with which the domain name will be associated
  * name, postal address, e-mail address, and voice and (where available) fax telephone numbers for the technical, administrative, billing, and zone contacts for the domain name

Once the domain name has been registered, your registration agreement requires you to correct and update this data promptly. We will support this by sending anual reminders for your domains to check their whois data. This is part of the [ICANN WDRP policy](https://joker.com/goto/icann_wdrp). If you submit a question about our service, you will be asked to provide your name and e-mail address. 

The information you provide when registering a domain name (or correcting or updating registration information) is required to allow us to establish a contractual relationship between you and Joker.com, to enable the Internet to associate the domain name with your computer, to allow us to properly handle your account (including notifying you when a domain name is about to expire), and to permit others operating or using the Internet to easily contact you to resolve issues that arise in connection with the domain name. It will also be stored under a data escrow program to keep the domain name operating in the event Joker.com terminates the domain name business. 

The data you provide for the registration or updates of domains has to be disclosed to 

  * our staff and consultants
  * the operator of the registry for the top-level domain in which you are registering
  * operators and users of the central Whois service associated with the top-level domain in which you are registering *)
  * ICANN, the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers as technical internet authority
  * escrow agents, auditors, Whois service providers
  * in case of necessity to replacement registrars that ICANN may designate

*) for many top level domains an optional privacy service can be chosen to display proxy contacts in public whois 

**Disclosure, detent, deletion**

You are always entitled to request information about your stored personal data, its origin and recipient, the purpose of the data processing and a right to correct, block or delete this data. To this end, as well as to further questions regarding the subject of personal data, you can contact us at any time at the address given in this imprint. 

**Server logs**

The provider of the pages automatically collects and saves information in so-called server log files, which your browser automatically transmits to us. These are in particular: 

  * type of Browser / version
  * operating system used
  * referring URL
  * time of the server request
  * IP address **anonymized for not-logged-in users**

This data can not be attributed to specific persons. This data is not merged with other data sources. We reserve the right to review this data at a later date, if concrete indications of unlawful use become known to us. 

**Privacy Policy for use of Piwik**

This website uses the open source web analytics service Piwik. Piwik uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and allow to analyze your use of the website. For this purpose, the information generated by the cookie about the use of this website is stored on our servers. The IP address is anonymised prior to storage. The information on the use of this website generated by the cookie is not passed on to third parties. You can prevent cookies from being saved by setting your browser software accordingly. However, we would like to point out that in this case you may not be able to fully utilize all the functions of this website. If you do not agree to the storage and use of your data, you can deactivate the storage and use here. In this case, an _opt-out cookie_ is stored in your browser, that prevents Piwik from storing user data. If you delete your cookies, this also means that the Piwik Opt-Out cookie is also deleted. The opt-out must be reactivated when you visit our site again. 

You are not being tracked since your browser is reporting that you do not want to. This is a setting of your browser so you won't be able to opt-in until you disable the 'Do Not Track' feature. 

**Contact form**

If you send us inquiries by means of a contact form, your information from the inquiry form, including the contact data you provide there, will be saved by us for the purpose of processing the inquiry and for the case of follow-up questions. We do not pass on this data without your consent. 

#### Responsible Organization

The responsible authority within the meaning of the Bundesdatenschutzgesetz is: 

    CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH
    Hansaallee 191-193
    D-40549 Duesseldorf
    Fax: +49 211 86767 6449
    www.csl.de

#### Privacy Officer

If you have further questions about our privacy policy, please do not hesitate to contact our appointed data protection officer. Please make use of the CSL contact information. 

#### The Right to Withdraw

**Instructions**

As a consumer, you have the right to revoke your purchase contract within fourteen days without giving reasons. The revocation period is fourteen days from the date of conclusion of the contract.   
To exercise your right of withdrawal, you must provide us with a clear declaration (e.g. a letter, fax or e-mail sent by post) about your decision to revoke this contract. In order to comply with the revocation period, it is sufficient that you send the notice of the exercise of the revocation right before the expiry of the revocation period. The revocation is to be addressed to: 

**CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH d/b/a Joker.com**  
Hansaallee 191-193  
DE-40549 Düsseldorf  
Germany  
Fax: +49 211 86767 6449  
Contact: [info[AT]joker[DOT]com](https://joker.com/goto/support)

**Consequences of Withdrawal**

If you withdraw from this agreement, we will refund all payments we have received from you, including delivery costs (with the exception of the additional costs resulting from your choosing a different type of delivery than the cheapest standard delivery offered by us) , immediately and at the latest within fourteen days from the day we receive notice of your withdrawal from this agreement. We will use the same means of payment for this refund as you used for the original transaction, unless expressly agreed otherwise with you; in no event will you be charged any fees for this refund. We may refuse to refund until we have received the goods back or until you can prove that you have returned the goods, whichever is earlier. If you have agreed that the performance of the contract shall commence during the withdrawal period, you shall pay us a reasonable amount equal to the proportion of the services already provided up to the time you notify us of the exercise of the right of withdrawal in respect of this contract in relation to the total amount of services provided for in the contract. 

**Information regarding Domain Contracts**

The right of withdrawal and return for distance contracts is excluded for consumer contracts for the delivery of goods, which are manufactured according to customer specifications or individual selection and determination of the customer, or are clearly tailored to personal needs. The customer agrees that Joker.com starts immediately after conclusion of the contract with the execution of the service. When placing service orders in relation to domain names, the client expressly agrees that the order will be executed immediately upon placement. The right of withdrawal and return is expressly excluded for customers who are not consumers. 

**Sample withdrawal form**

(If you want to cancel the contract, please fill out this form and send it back to us.) 

      CSL Computer Service Langenbach GmbH d/b/a Joker.com
      Hansaallee 191-193
      DE-40549 Düsseldorf
      Germany
      Fax: +49 211 86767 6449
      E-Mail: info[AT]joker[DOT]com
    
      - I/we (*) hereby cancel the contract concluded by me/us (*)
        on the purchase of the following goods (*)/
        the provision of the following service (*)
      - Ordered on (*)/received on (*)
      - Name(s) of consumer(s)
      - Customer number of the consumer(s)
      - Address of consumer(s)
      - Signature of consumer(s) (only for paper communication)
      - date
      (*) Delete as appropriate.
